researchworld.org 2011-10-06

# ESOMAR - Privacy Policy

**This is the Privacy Policy of ESOMAR B.V. and The Society of ESOMAR (“ESOMAR”).**

**ESOMAR, as Controller, complies with the Personal Data Protection Act of the Netherlands, which is based on the EU Data Protection directive.**

## What is Personal Data?

Personal data is the information that identifies you, such as your name, address, email or postal address.

## What is it used for?

ESOMAR collects and processes personal data of members and customers. ESOMAR is convinced that a privacy policy is of utmost importance.

ESOMAR respects the personal data of members and customers and does not sell, rent, loan, trade or otherwise transfer any personal data to any third party unless this is necessary to deliver ESOMAR’s products and services.

ESOMAR does not request personal data from you, other than to process a transaction or application for ESOMAR membership and/or company listing in the ESOMAR Directory, a registration for an ESOMAR event, or an order for an ESOMAR publication, such as the online Directory of members* or for analytical research.

ESOMAR will also use your personal data to inform you about activities, products and services of ESOMAR and relevant third parties, unless you have notified ESOMAR that you do not to wish to receive such information.

ESOMAR will only share your personal information with a third party if you expressly ask to receive information from them. Please note that to stop receiving information from a third party, you will need to contact them directly.

*Only Members are entitled to access the Directory of Members.

## The use of e-mail

ESOMAR will only use the e-mail address of member and customers, outside the scope of membership or a transaction, for the purpose where a member and/or customer has given opt-in. ESOMAR will always provide you in every e-mail, where relevant, with an unsubscribe link.

Receiving information by e-mail, means that you receive the latest information and updates that can have an effect on your day-by-day operation.

If any customer or members’ personal data, or information provided in the ESOMAR Member Directory or the Directory of Research Organisations is incorrect or out-of-date, please contact us in writing (or email with the necessary changes): [customerservice@esomar.org](mailto:customerservice@esomar.org)

## The Directory of ESOMAR Members

The Directory of ESOMAR Members may not be used for mailings, electronic or otherwise for direct marketing purposes. Unsolicited commercial email for sales or promotional purposes is spam and is illegal in many countries. ESOMAR recognises the importance of data privacy regulations and reminds members that they are responsible for any misuse of the Directory within their organisation or by third parties contracted to provide their organisation with services.

Members should not send unsolicited email to other members unless it is for a specific purpose relating to that member eg to ask for a bid for a project.

ESOMAR reserves the right to withdraw membership services from those who misuse the Directory. ESOMAR reserves also the right of seed-addresses to monitor the use of the Directory in accordance with this policy.

## Links to Other Websites

This privacy policy only applies to www.esomar.org. This privacy policy does not extend to third party websites.

## How to opt out?

If you do not wish to receive information about ESOMAR's activities, products and/or services or offers of other relevant third parties, please inform us through our [online form](http://visitor.constantcontact.com/manage/optin/ea?v=001_D6q8SmIH1obPhVvmZLuKw==) or by mail or email at the following address:

ESOMAR  
Eurocenter 2, 11th floor  
Barbara Strozzilaan 384  
1083 HN Amsterdam  
The Netherlands  
Tel: +31 20 664 2141  
Fax: +31 20 664 2922  
Email: [customerservice@esomar.org](mailto:customerservice@esomar.org)

## Updating your Personal / Company Information?

If any personal data, or information provided in the ESOMAR Directory of Members or the Directory of Research Organisations is incorrect or out-of-date, please email the necessary changes to: [customerservice@esomar.org](mailto:customerservice@esomar.org)

If you have any questions about ESOMAR’s Privacy Policy, please contact: [k.joe@esomar.org](mailto:k.joe@esomar.org)

## Use of cookies

A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your computer browser from a website's computer and is stored on your computer, if your browser’s preferences allow it. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser but (to protect your privacy) your browser only permits a website to access its own cookies, not the cookies sent to you by other sites.

You have the opportunity to set your device to accept all cookies, to notify you when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. Information supplied by cookies can help ESOMAR to analyse the profile of our visitors and help us to provide you with a better user experience.

ESOMAR uses cookies to:

  * track online traffic flow (through Google Analytics and Google AdManager)
  * enable login to the different sessions (My ESOMAR/Directory /Career network)
  * personalize the information in online forms

## Applicable Law

This privacy policy is governed by and construed in accordance with the law of the Netherlands. All disputes arising out of or in connection with this privacy policy must be dealt with under the jurisdiction of the courts of the Netherlands.

## Amendments

ESOMAR reserves the right to change any of the terms of this privacy policy at any time and without notice. ESOMAR therefore recommends that you review this privacy policy from time to time, or before making a transaction.

Amsterdam, 1 February 2011
